<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2024 Slack Technologies, Inc. -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.slack.Slack</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <developer_name>Slack Technologies Inc.</developer_name>
  <project_group>Slack Technologies Inc.</project_group>
  <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary</project_license>
  <name>Slack</name>
  <summary>Team communication for the 21st century</summary>

  <url type="homepage">https://slack.com</url>
  <url type="help">https://get.slack.help</url>

  <description>
    <p>Caution: Slack for Linux is in beta. We’re still busy adding features and
    ironing out potential issues.</p>
    <p>Slack brings team communication and collaboration into one place so you can get
    more work done, whether you belong to a large enterprise or a small business.
    Check off your to-do list and move your projects forward by bringing the right
    people, conversations, tools, and information you need together. Slack is
    available on any device, so you can find and access your team and your work,
    whether you’re at your desk or on the go.</p>
    <p>Scientifically proven (or at least rumored) to make your working life simpler,
    more pleasant, and more productive. We hope you’ll give Slack a try.</p>
    <p>Stop by and learn more at: https://slack.com/</p>
    <p>NOTE: This wrapper is not verified by, affiliated with, or supported by Slack
    Technologies, Inc.</p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.slack.Slack.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot environment="gnome:dark" type="default">
      <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.slack.Slack/master/screenshots/gnome-dark-general-slack.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot environment="gnome:dark">
      <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.slack.Slack/master/screenshots/gnome-dark-messages-slack.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot environment="gnome">
      <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.slack.Slack/master/screenshots/gnome-light-general-slack.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot environment="gnome">
      <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.slack.Slack/master/screenshots/gnome-light-messages-slack.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <categories>
    <category>InstantMessaging</category>
    <category>Network</category>
  </categories>

  <provides>
    <mediatype>x-scheme-handler/slack</mediatype>
  </provides>

  <supports>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>touch</control>
    <display_length compare="ge">medium</display_length>
  </supports>

  <requires>
    <internet bandwidth_mbitps="2">always</internet>
  </requires>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-audio">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-info">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>

  <update_contact>akoskovich_at_protonmail.com</update_contact>

  <!-- Contents are from https://slack.com/release-notes/linux -->
  <releases>
    <release version="4.36.138" date="2024-01-16">
      <description>
        <p>All bugs that were fixed in this release were too small for the eye to
        see or too fiddly for human words to describe. Nevertheless, work was done,
        things tinkered with and the app became subtly better.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.36.136" date="2023-12-21">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.36.134" date="2023-12-11">
      <description>
        <p>We don’t have anything in particular to call out for this release, but we
        thank you for staying up to date all the same.</p>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.35.132" date="2023-12-21">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.35.131" date="2023-11-30">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.35.130" date="2023-11-27">
      <description>
        <p>Changes are afoot when it comes to updating the Linux app.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.35.126" date="2023-11-6">
      <description>
        <p>Changes are afoot when it comes to updating the Linux app.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.35.121" date="2023-10-24">
      <description>
        <p>All bugs that were fixed in this release were too small for the eye to see
        or too fiddly for human words to describe. Nevertheless, work was done, things
        tinkered with and the app became subtly better.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.34.121" date="2023-09-28">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.34.120" date="2023-09-13">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.34.115" date="2023-09-05">
      <description>
        <p>Starting with Slack for Linux version 4.34, a new code signing key will be used.</p>
        <p>Linux users on Wayland noticed that screensharing in huddles would crash the app
        as soon as sharing ended. No good deed goes unpunished, they say. We’re working to
        change that to "No bad bug goes unfixed." Please resume sharing with impunity.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.33.90" date="2023-08-14">
      <description>
        <p>We tuned up the engine and gave the interiors a thorough clean. Everything is now
        running smoothly again.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.33.84" date="2023-07-31">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
        <p>We’ll be using a new code signing key starting from release 4.34 to verify Slack
        for Linux package signatures.</p>
        <p>On Sept. 1, we’ll be deprecating support for some older operating systems and
        outdated versions of Slack.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.33.73" date="2023-06-28">
      <description>
        <p>Intelligent quips often contain depth of thought, but that’s not what we mean
        when we say that smartquotes were presenting a problem for deep links. Punctuation
        will no longer affect the punctuality of your deep link updates.</p>
        <p>Good governance is all about removing roadblocks, which is why we’ve retooled
        the sign-in flow for GovSlack. Now when you sign in to a government workspace for
        the first time, we’ll automatically restart the app in Gov mode (instead of kicking
        you back to the login page). Your Slack dollars at work!</p>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.32.127" date="2023-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>We tuned up the engine and gave the interiors a thorough clean. Everything is
        now running smoothly again.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.32.122" date="2023-05-10">
      <description>
        <p>For some users, a successful connection to VPN resulted in an unsuccessful
        connection of Slack to the internet, which of course made working in Slack impossible.
        We’ve set you up for success once again by successfully fixing this issue.</p>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.31.155" date="2023-04-12">
      <description>
        <p>Organizations will be able to manage Slack desktop client settings during rollout
        and ongoing operations. Configurations can be deployed with industry standard tooling:
        Group Policies on Windows, user preferences profiles on Mac and with configuration files
        on Linux.</p>
        <p>Those of you who love approaching meetings with all the mystery of a blind date no
        doubt enjoyed our recent bug where huddle invitations wouldn’t say which workspace or
        channel they came from. Everyone else thought this was weird and confusing, so we
        fixed it.</p>
        <p>Using the shortcut Ctrl + Shift + F will now toggle to Fullscreen mode, allowing
        you to really take in the view (or just focus a bit more).</p>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.29.149" date="2022-11-28">
      <description>
        <p>“What is this—a video player for ants?” YouTube videos embedded in Slack can now be
        expanded to play in full-screen mode, which we’re told is at least three times bigger.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.28.184" date="2022-09-27"/>
    <release version="4.28.182" date="2022-09-26">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.28.171" date="2022-08-31">
      <description>
        <p>On Sept. 1, we’ll be deprecating support for some older operating systems and outdated
        versions of Slack.</p>
        <p>Starting with Slack for Linux version 4.28, a new code signing key will be used.</p>
        <p>Trying to capture your screen with a third-party app while also sharing your screen
        in Slack may have resulted in the non-Slack app crashing. We’d like to say that this
        was because the idea of “capture” is antithetical to “sharing,” but in truth it was
        just a “bug.”</p>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.27.156" date="2022-07-05">
      <description>
        <p>We tuned up the engine and gave the interiors a thorough clean. Everything is now
        running smoothly again.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.27.154" date="2022-06-27">
      <description>
        <p>You may have noticed that with this release there’s a new, larger number at the end
        of the version string. Going forward, while you’ll still see the numbers laid out in a
        MAJOR.MINOR.BUILD sequence, the “Build” numbers will now correspond to specific builds
        on our end as opposed to a small sequential number. TL;DR: A few more numbers for you,
        a bit more specificity for everyone.</p>
        <p>We’ve added the most common Apple and Microsoft file extensions to our approved list
        so you won’t be asked to confirm each time you open a Word doc or Keynote presentation.
        Are you sure you’d like one less approval? YES/NO</p>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.26.1" date="2022-05-16">
      <description>
        <p>If you tried to re-download a file that was already present in your Downloads folder,
        the app would pretend to download it again without actually producing a new file.
        Duplicitous duplication was never part of the plan—sorry about that.</p>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.25.1" date="2022-04-04">
      <description>
        <p>We’ve tinkered with the internal workings and polished some rough edges. The app is now
        better than it was.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.25.0" date="2022-04-04">
      <description>
        <p>Starting today, you’ll see a confirmation pop-up when a link in Slack is prompting another
        program to open. If you don’t want to see these each time because you enjoy living on the edge,
        just check the box “Always open files of this type.”</p>
        <p>We discovered that under very specific circumstances (stars being aligned, barometric pressure
        being just so, looking in a mirror and saying “Slackbot” 3 times), Active Directory users were
        ending up with a backslash in their Home directory, which was preventing the app from launching.
        However it happened, all slashes are welcome at the party, so Slack will run as expected now.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.24.1" date="2022-03-17">
      <description>
        <p>We’ve updated our Linux package to use strict confinement for additional security sandboxing
        and faster loading times. That’s what we call a Win/Win (or a Linux/Linux).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.24.0" date="2022-03-14">
      <description>
        <p>Perhaps you wanted to know which version of the app you had installed. Maybe we gave you an
        option to copy that version number to your clipboard. It’s possible the “Copy” button didnothing
        at all. One might say we fixed it.</p>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.23.0" date="2021-12-13">
      <description>
        <p>If you are someone who moved your app data directory and were using a symlink, you may have
        noticed that Slack would fail to open beyond the initial launch. Well, now it won’t do that
        anymore. We fixed it, you see.</p>
        <p>Some external URLs were occasionally launching within the Slack app window, but will now load
        in your default web browser, as is proper. Slack cannot have a little web page, even as a treat.</p>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.22.0" date="2021-11-16">
      <description>
        <p>Starting with Slack for Linux version 4.22.0, a new code signing key will be used. Please visit
        this Help Center article for new instructions on signature verification</p>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.21.1" date="2021-11-04">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
        <p>A new way to verify package signatures for Linux - We’ll soon be using a new code signing key to
        verify Slack for Linux package signatures.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.20.0" date="2021-09-29">
      <description>
        <p>When opening SSH, FTP, SFTP or SMB links, you’ll now see the option to allow all future URLs
        from just that same domain instead of the whole wide world. A little more secure for us, a little
        more peace of mind for you.</p>
        <p>We fixed a crash that was occurring on certain Linux clients, as studies have shown that Slack
        works better when it doesn’t sporadically quit without warning.</p>
        <p>Certain versions of the app were not correctly changing availability to “Away” after 10 minutes
        of inactivity. While this has been fixed, we’d like to remind you that you can use your Custom Status
        to let your teammates know your whereabouts beyond simply Active or Away. Examples include: walking
        the dog, catching up after PTO, taking a mental break, or tweeting nice things to the Slack social
        media team.</p>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.19.2" date="2021-08-23">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes significant security improvements. Updating is strongly recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.18.0" date="2021-07-27">
      <description>
        <p>Certain menus were not being properly translated when switching languages in the app. You know
        what they say about menus — they’re most helpful when you can read them.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.17.0" date="2021-06-27">
      <description>
        <p>Bigger is better, or rather, closer is clearer. We now support additional zoom levels up to
        200% to reduce the strain on your precious peepers.</p>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.16.0" date="2021-05-11">
      <description>
        <p>Images and notifications were sometimes sharing real estate...inelegantly. We have given them
        both a talking-to, and they have agreed to joint custody of that section of the screen.</p>
        <p>This release includes security improvements. Updating is recommended.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.15.0" date="2021-04-23">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.14.0" date="2021-03-17">
      <description>
        <p>We improved the restart experience when you’ve gone offline or are having loading issues.</p>
        <p>We all have to sign out sometimes. If you sign out of all of your workspaces, you should have
        an easier time signing back in.</p>
        <p>This release includes minor security improvements. Updating is beneficial.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.13.0" date="2021-02-17">
      <description>
        <p>When you move or resize Slack, we assume you are indeed trying to move or resize it — and so the
        crash that was regularly happening, instead, was unwelcome. We’ve fixed this. Here’s to properly-sized
        screens!</p>
        <p>We’ve fixed several accessibility issues. Making Slack more accessible is a continuous journey,
        and we’re quite grateful that you’re along for the ride!</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.12.2" date="2021-01-08">
      <description>
        <p>We tweaked some things too small to notice or too difficult to explain. We’ll return you to your
        regular, more interesting types of release next time (we hope).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.12.1" date="2021-01-07">
      <description>
        <p>We tuned up the engine and gave the interiors a thorough clean. Everything is now running smoothly
        again.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.12.0" date="2020-12-14">
      <description>
        <p>È pronto! Italian language support has landed!</p>
        <p>As a dancer gracefully recovers from a minor tumble, so shall our app gracefully reload whilst
        throttled by network failures.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.11.3" date="2020-11-25">
      <description>
        <p>We’ve tinkered with the internal workings and polished some rough edges. The app is now better
        than it was.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.11.1" date="2020-11-11">
      <description>
        <p>We tweaked some things too small to notice or too difficult to explain. We’ll return you to your
        regular, more interesting types of release next time (we hope).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.11.0" date="2020-11-09">
      <description>
        <p>We tuned up the engine and gave the interiors a thorough clean. Everything is now running
        smoothly again.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.10.3" date="2020-10-15">
      <description>
        <p>We’ve tinkered with the internal workings and polished some rough edges. The app is now
        better than it was.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.10.0" date="2020-10-08">
      <description>
        <p>We fixed some issues that caused window resizing of Slack to be difficult. We never want
        to be difficult.</p>
        <p>Quickly switching workspaces caused problems. Switching workspaces should only cause
        opportunities, so we fixed that.</p>
        <p>There were a few little bugs that caused crashes, like bugs do. We fixed those, and we’ll
        fix the next ones too.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.9.1" date="2020-09-17">
      <description>
        <p>We tuned up the engine and gave the interiors a thorough clean. Everything is now running
        smoothly again.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.8.0" date="2020-07-20">
      <description>
        <p>In rare cases, Slack would simply fail to start altogether. While we’re sure we could all
        use a coffee break, we know you could also use an application that runs. So we fixed that.</p>
        <p>We made the screen you see when you have connection problems more useful. We also spruced
        it up a bit with a fresh coat of paint.</p>
        <p>Our notifications system sprung a leak, so we brought it in for a tune-up. Everything
        should be running smoother now.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.7.0" date="2020-07-03">
      <description>
        <p>A preference that allows you to choose a unique save location per download, instead of
        choosing a folder for all of them. For the choosy types.</p>
        <p>We’ve upgraded all the backend stuff that the apps run on, resulting in better performance
        and fewer bugs.</p>
        <p>Our spell checker has been swapped out for a newer model that’s faster, leaner, and capable
        of fixing your typos in… wait, can this be right? “Multiple languages at the same time”! Open
        the “Language and Region” preferences to choose your languages. And for whoever it is out there
        requires that functionality: our hats are off to you. We can barely type in one language right now.</p>
        <p>After restoring the app window, some parts of it could lose their clickiness. Those parts have
        found their clickiness anew. Click away. Clickety clickety click.</p>
        <p>If you found yourself, in some distant past, trying to start a song on Spotify with your keyboard’s
        play button, and it did not respond to your command while Slack was front and center, pesky hardware
        media keys were the problem. And this version is the cure.</p>
        <p>The app should be less spicy to your CPU when you’re viewing certain network error pages.</p>
        <p>When a download completes, we’ll show an in-app prompt rather than a bothersome system notification.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.4.3" date="2020-05-18">
      <description>
        <p>We’ve tinkered with the internal workings and polished some rough edges. The app is now better
        than it was.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.4.2" date="2020-03-31">
      <description>
        <p>We’re always working on performance improvements - and this release repairs a previously broken
        performance diagnostic tool. You won’t notice a difference, but we’ll have an easier time improving
        Slack.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.4.0" date="2020-02-04">
      <description>
        <p>Fixed: If you zoom way in or zoom way out, and then open the About Slack window, the About Slack
        window would also be zoomed way in/out.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.3.2" date="2020-01-30">
      <description>
        <p>We’ve tinkered with the internal workings and polished some rough edges. The app is now better
        than it was.</p>
        <p>Slack would sometimes crash when the user right-clicked to see the context menu. In context,
        that was unhelpful. So it no longer does that.</p>
        <p>When maximized, the app had developed a bit of a distracting flicker. That flicker is now part
        of Slack history.</p>
        <p>Occasionally, a restart would result in connectivity issues for Slack… now you should be back
        online and back to work lickety-split.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.2.0" date="2019-12-05">
      <description>
        <p>Our newest, fastest, best-performing, shiniest, most nutritious and delicious version of Slack
        is now fully rolled out, so that’s the one you’re now using. Brilliant.</p>
        <p>Like zooming in and out? Use a numpad? Great news. You can now do these things, on that.</p>
        <p>Notifications looked weird if your workspace name was long. Now, no matter your team name,
        notifications look lovely.</p>
        <p>Some messages were being marked as read when Slack was hidden behind applications, or not
        visible on screen. Now we won’t mark it as read until you’ve actually seen it. Which seems fair.</p>
        <p>In Linux some components of the app were displaying menus when menus were not required. These
        items are now officially off-menu. Or rather, the menu is now officially off-them.</p>
        <p>By popular demand (and because it was a bug), the --silent option is now available to silence
        terminal output.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.1.2" date="2019-10-18">
      <description>
        <p>Receiving a gif in a notification could mess with your notifications.</p>
        <p>Long workspace names now no longer appear as incredibly long in menus.</p>
        <p>Slack menus should now be showing up at the right language (meaning the one that is right
        for you).</p>
        <p>Spellchecker stopped working for a small count of users, leading to a shorp uptick in
        avoidabull erratz. With spellcheck now fully back online for those users, any remaining
        typos are officially not our fault.</p>
        <p>Restarting when clearing cache now works again.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.1.1" date="2019-10-08">
      <description>
        <p>Thanks to a few tweaks to the engine, a polish of the pistons, and recalibrated valves,
        the app should be running smoother and faster, than before.</p>
        <p>Spellcheck, revamped, is now a much better version of its old self (and back on Linux,
        to boot) — now it supports Greek, Portuguese and British English. So now spelling correctly
        should come more naturally to us all (which is good, because “correctly” can be a difacult
        word to spell).</p>
        <p>For a quicker connection, and less frustration, checking for network connectivity is more
        reliable than it was before.</p>
        <p>After uploading a video into Slack some found it would give an infinite circle of loading,
        but not play, which was never our plan. Now: it works! It plays; no more circle! Because, it
        turned out, all circ and no play made Slack a null ‘ploy.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.0.2" date="2019-08-07">
      <description>
        <p>Videos in channels were found to be the cause of a minor (but pesky) memory leak that has
        now been well and truly plugged.</p>
        <p>We spruced up the notifications a little so now they’ll not only show up every time you
        need them to, they’ll show up looking like whatever theme you wear proudly on your sidebar. Neat.</p>
        <p>On opening your computer, the app is now, thankfully, more likely to launch properly every time.</p>
        <p>If you’d become used to opening Slack from a shortcut on your desktop or menu… you’ll know
        that we broke that recently. Sorry about that. It is now unbroken once more.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.0.1" date="2019-07-25">
      <description>
        <p>We’ve tinkered with the internal workings and polished some rough edges. The app is now better
        than it was.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.0.0" date="2019-07-08"/>
    <release version="3.4.2" date="2019-05-23"/>
    <release version="3.4.0" date="2019-04-18"/>
    <release version="3.3.8" date="2019-03-12"/>
    <release version="3.3.7" date="2019-01-16"/>
    <release version="3.3.3" date="2018-10-02"/>
    <release version="3.3.1" date="2018-08-31"/>
    <release version="3.2.1" date="2018-05-31"/>
  </releases>
</component>
